Infinite space. Infinite terror.
Event Horizon is a horror, science fiction, mystery
film directed by Paul W. S. Anderson.
In 2047, a group of astronauts are sent to investigate and salvage the starship Event
Horizon which disappeared mysteriously seven years before on its maiden voyage.
However, it soon becomes evident that something
sinister resides in its corridors.
Miller, played by Laurence Fishburne.
Weir, played by Sam Neill.
Peters, played by Kathleen Quinlan.
Starck, played by Joely Richardson.
Cooper, played by Richard T. Jones.
Justin, played by Jack Noseworthy.
Event Horizon is a 1997 science fiction horror film directed
by Paul Anderson and written by Philip Eisner.
It stars Laurence Fishburne, Sam Neill, Kathleen Quinlan, and Joely Richardson.
The film follows a crew of astronauts in the year 2047 who are sent on a rescue mission after the Event Horizon, a
spaceship that went missing seven years earlier, spontaneously reappears in orbit around Neptune.
The film had a troubled production, with filming and editing rushed by Paramount Pictures
when it became clear that Titanic would not meet its projected release.
The original 130-minute cut of the film was heavily edited by the
studio's demand, much to Anderson's consternation.
Event Horizon was released in the United States on 15 August
1997 and the United Kingdom one week later.
It was a commercial and critical failure, grossing
$42 million on a $60 million budget.
However, it sold well on home video; its initial DVD release sold so well that Paramount contacted Anderson to
begin working on a restoration of the deleted footage, but it had been either lost or destroyed.
The film has since been reassessed as a cult classic that influenced many sci-fi and horror films
and video games, and has appeared on lists of the best horror films of all time.
In 2025, Event Horizon: Dark Descent, a comic book prequel
series began being published by IDW Publishing.
In 2026, Event Horizon: Inferno, a comic book sequel series, is
set to begin being published by IDW Publishing.
The film explores themes of space marine, nightmare,
insanity, delusion, hallucination.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and mind_bending.